So in this presentation we will be talking about NFC forum.
So NFC forum is a non-profit trade association that promotes the use of the near-field communication
technology, which is NFC.
The mission of the NFC forum is to encourage the use of NFC technology by first developing standards
based specification to ensure interoperability between devices and services.
Second, encouraging the development of products using the NFC forum.
Specifications.
Third globally, promoting NFC technology.
And finally ensuring that NFC equipment complies with NFC forum specifications.
Becoming a member of NFC forum grants you access to a community of experts in the field of near field
communication technology.
As a member, you will have exclusive access to the latest research, industry insights and networking
opportunities with other professionals who shares your passion for NFC.
In addition, membership provides you with the opportunity to contribute to the development of new standards
and technologies that will shape the future of NFC.
By working together with other members, you can help to create innovative solutions that will drive
growth and increase adoption of NFC technology worldwide.
For example, there are some sponsor members like Apple, Google and NXP, and others that shapes the
mission and direction of the organization at all levels for every market.
There are also principal members who hold a strategic level of leadership, participation and influence
on NFC forum deliverables and first party testing privileges.
For example, Mastercard, visa, Samsung, and honor.
What about NFC forum specifications?
In fact, there are five NFC forum specifications and the first one is an Ndef specification.
NFC data exchange format, which is a common format for data exchange between hardware and NFC forum
compatible tags.
It also contains the rules for constructing a valid Ndef message and the workable set of Ndef records.
The second one is RTD specification record type definition.
It ensures the interoperability of NFC technology across multiple hardware categories.
Then we have Smart Poster RTD specification.
This specification defines a type of record allowing to insert URLs, URLs, SMS, or telephone numbers
on NFC tag by titling them.
The fourth one is text RTD specification.
Record type.
Description.
Record type correspond to plain text data.
This specification corresponds to a general purpose text field used to add metadata to objects like
URLs, with a reduced footprint.
And then the last one you are I.
RTD specification uniform resource identifier.
Service record.
Type.
Description.
The URI RTD specification describes the record used with the Ndef specification to retrieve a URI Uniform
Resource Identifier.
This specification also allows URIs to be stored inside other NFC items such as smart posters.
So for NFC forum tags, there are different types.
In fact, the NFC forum organized tags in five types.
Each of them correspond to different tools.
I'm going here to show you the different characteristics of each type and the associated uses.
For example the first one NFC tags type one.
This type of tags can be can be read and write.
It operates under the norm ISO 14,443.
By the way, we will discuss later in detail about this standard.
The ISO 14,443 is a very important standard about contactless communication, and we need to detail
through this whole training.
So let's get back to the NFC tag type one.
So the protocol simplicity allow us to reduce the number of electronic components and thus to reduce
the cost of the tag.
In return the communication flow is limited and only the basic functionalities can be implemented.
Basic functionalities like read, write, lock.
The type one tags are used for some applications like business cards, pairing devices with Bluetooth
and reading a specific tag when more than one tag is present.
Then we have the NFC tags.
Type two.
This type of tags is compliant with NFC, the technology of communication type A, but by the way,
because in the contactless communication we have different types.
We have type A, type B, ISO 15 for the vicinity and felica.
So so this tag type two, it can operate on two modes read and write mode but also read only mode.
It operates under the norm ISO 14,443.
The NFC forum type two tag is the most popular type of tag.
It offers a solution to a wide range of needs and uses at affordable price.
The type two tags are faster than type one tags, and are used in applications where users need instant
communication.
The type two tags are used for some applications like low value transactions and De transit passes.
Then we have the NFC tags.
Type three.
This type of tags is compliant with NFC if it can read and write, but also read only.
It operates under the norm GIS 6319.
For this norm, the standard refers to the felica communication the Japanese communication Japanese
type of cards.
The type three NFC forum tags operates under a different norm than the other tags types.
This text components are more sophisticated than the two others, and this tag provides a lot of features,
for example identification and digital world and comes with a relatively high price.
The type three tags are used for some applications like transit tickets, e-money, electronic ID membership
cards, e-tickets, health care devices, and home electronics.
The fourth one we have NFC tags type four.
This type of tags is compliant with NFC and NFC.
It can read, write, and read only.
It operates under the standard ISO 14,443, four A and B.
The type four tag offers use, flexibility and wide memory.
The price of the stock is moderate to high depending on the amount of memory chosen.
Security is the most important features of this type of tag.
It allows you to realize through identification.
So the type four tags is the only type of tags that can support the needed level of security for ISO
7816, and it also allows modification of Ndef content.
This capability allows, for example, to answer to transit ticket application requirements.
Finally, we have the type five NFC tags.
This type of tags is compliant with NFC for vicinity, V for vicinity.
It can read, write, and read only.
It operates under the standard ISO 15,693.
It allows to transfer data between technology already supported by NFC forum, and the technical specification
of the ISO 15,693.
The reading distance is better than the one of other tags, and the tag that supports type five tag
will be able to support ISO 15,693 tags.
The type five tags are used for some applications like library books, products and packaging ticketing.
For example such ski passes and health care such like medication packaging.
And here, here we are in the summary.
So I just took four notes from what we have seen together in this presentation.
So NFC forum is an association that promotes the use of the NFC technology, became a member of NFC
forum, grants you access to a community of experts in the field of near-field communication technology.
NFC forum has five specifications and the NFC forum organized tags in five types, each of them corresponding
to different uses.